Guide to the Charles McKinney Papers, 1952-1993 and undated RL.00878
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings and Speeches, 1952-1990 and undated, 3 boxes
  - Reports by others, 1966-1988 and undated
    - Print and Broadcast Traffic System, Humphrey Browining MacDougal, 1981 (Box 48)
    - Profile of Compensation Programs for Marketing Personnel, H. Heery, 1990 (Box 49)
    - Sales Promotions: A Reference Book to Aid in Promotion Planning, Ketchum, MacLeod & Grove, undated (Box 49)
    - Sequential Analysis: Framework for Determining Marketing Strategy, McKinsey & Col, 1972 (Box 49)
    - Survey of Advertiser-Agency Relations, Nancy Salz Consulting, 1990 (Box 49)
    - Testing T.V. Commercials, Henderson Agency, 1972 (Box 49)
    - U.S. Economy in 1990, Conference Board, 1972 (Box 49)
  - Speeches by others, 1961-1985 and undated
    - AAAA convention speeches, 1961 (Box 49)
    - Bank Marketing Association Conference speech, T. Renand, undated (Box 49)
    - Does It Pay for Agencies to Advertise, R. Christian, 1967 (Box 49)
    - Eleven Ways to Waste Your Advertising Appropriation, H. Sawyer, 1971 (Box 49)
    - How to Recruit and Keep Good People, C. Meade, 1985 (Box 49)
    - Importance of Finding Decision Maker for Retail Services, R.J. Baran, 1975 (Box 49)
    - Importance of Finding Decision Maker for Retail Services, R.J. Baran, 1975 (Box 49)
    - Multi-Dimensional Scaling: An Overview, L. Percy, 1972 (Box 49)
    - New South, G.H. Brown, 1970 (Box 49)
    - Why I Wish to be Chancellor of North Carolina State University, B.C. Talley, Jr., 1981 (Box 49)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1972-1990 and undated, 7 boxes
  Contains various formats primarily of M&S advertising spots; promotional films; and presentation reels prepared by competitive agencies, including Angotti Thomas & Hedge, Bartle Bogle Hegarty Ltd., Boase Massimi Pollitt, Chiat Day, Fallon McElligott Rice, Goodby Berlin & Silverstein, and J. Walter Thompson. Includes two videos related to the 1988 Out of Towners Exhibition in New York City.
  M&S clients represented include Barnett Banks, Carolina Power & Light, GoodMark Foods, Inc., Kingsdown, Pine State, North Carolina National Bank, South Carolina National Bank, Mastercard, Royal Caribbean, Bahamas, Piedmont, Benihana, Brown & Williamson, and North Carolina DWI.
  Items were grouped by format and arranged alphabetically by title.
  - 16 mm films, 1972-1977 and undated (Box 50)
    - 1.-5. Barnett Banks, Baker, 1977, 5 copies (Box 50)
    - 6.-8. Barnett Banks, High Roller, 1975, 3 copies (Box 50)
    - 9. Barnett Banks, Interest on the Spot, Sisters, undated (Box 50)
    - 10.-16. Barnett Banks, Shrimp, 1977, 7 copies (Box 50)
    - 17.-21. Barnett Banks, Sleeper, 1977, 5 copies (Box 50)
    - 22.-24. Barnett Banks, Waitress, 1977, 3 copies (Box 50)
    - 25.-27. Carolina Power & Light, Weatherman, 1977 (Box 50)
    - 28.-29. D.L. Clark Company television commercial, Bars, 1977, 2 copies (Box 50)
    - 30.-32. GoodMark Foods, Inc., Jesse Jones Meats, Airplane, undated, 3 copies (Box 50)
    - 33.-36. GoodMark Foods, Inc., Jesse Jones Meats, Country Store, 1974, 4 copies (Box 50)
    - 37. Kingsdown Mattress, 1972 (Box 50)
    - 38.-41. North Carolina National Bank, Marriage License, undated, 4 copies (Box 50)
    - 42. Pine State, Chef, undated (Box 50)
    - 43.-47. Pine State, Milk Trek, undated, 5 copies (Box 50)
    - 48. South Carolina National Bank, Dock, 1977 (Box 50)
    - 49.-51. South Carolina National Bank, Homes, 1977, 3 copies (Box 50)
  - VHS, 1986-1989 and undated (Box 51)
    - 52. Bartle Bogle Hegarty compilation, 1987 (Box 51)
    - Crash, Time magazine story, 1987 (Box 51)
    - 54. Mastercard, Spendthrift, undated (Box 51)
    - McKinney & Silver
      - 55. Bahamas, Ministry of Tourism, Just Maybe, undated (Box 51)
      - 56.-58. Last 20 Years, undated, 3 copies (Box 51)
      - 59.-60. Presentation reel, 1986, 3 copies (Box 51)
      - 61. Royal Caribbean Cruise Line, 1980s; 0:02:30 (Box 51, Video-cassette RL00878-VHS-0001, Digital-materials RL00878-SET-0001)
        Scope and Contents
        Middle of Nowhere :30; Details :30; Fresh Flowers :30; The Show :30; My Private Island :30
      - 62. Royal Caribbean Cruise Line, 21 spots, 1980s; 0:12:15 (Box 51, Video-cassette RL00878-VHS-0002, Digital-materials RL00878-SET-0001)
        "GOOD MARRIAGE" 7 NIGHT CARIBBEAN $599; "SHUT INS" 3 NIGHT BAJA $299; "RIGHT ABOUT You" 7 NIGHT MEXICO$599; "YOUR CHILDREN" 3 NIGHT BAHAMAS $299; "ROCKED TO SLEEP" 7 NIGHT MEXICO $599; "SHE'S GOING ASHORE" 7 NIGHT CARIBBEAN $599; "HAVE A HONEYMOON" 7 NIGHT BERMUDA $599; " HAVE A HONEYMOON " 7 NIGHT BERMUDA $599; "TERRIBLE Twos" 7 NIGHT CARIBBEAN $599; "HOLIDAY/ TURt',F,:YS" 1-8OO-FOR-RCCL; "LAZY Boy" 7 NIGHT CARIBBEAN $599; "MIDNIGHT BUFFET" 3 NIGHT BAHAMAS $299; "DRIFT TOGETHER" 3 NIGHT BAJA$299; "LOVE Is PATIENT; KIND" 3 NIGHT BAJA $299; "LIKE AT HOME .... IN HIS DREAMS" 7 NIGHT MEXICO $599 "BEER/ FOOD/ GOLF" 3 NIGHT BAJA $299; "ENDS OF THE EARTH" 7 NIGHT ALASKA$599; "HEART IN THE SAME PLACE" I 2 NIGHT EUROPE; "MINIVAN" 3 NIGHT BAJA $299; "GOLF" 7 NIGHT GOLF $599; "COLUMBUS DAY" 3 NIGHT BAHAMAS $299
    - 63. Print's Best International Commercials, 1989 (Box 51)
    - 64. Termites and Men, undated (Box 52)
  - Umatic, 1988-1989 and undated
    - 65. Angotti Thomas & Hedge, BMPP Showreel, 1987-1988 (Box 52)
    - 66. Bartle Bogle Hegarty Ltd., presentation reel, 1988 (Box 52)
      [Includes spots for Audi, Pretty Polly, British Telecom, Puma, K Shoes, Allied Dunbar, Moosehead Manufacturing Co. and Levi Strauss & Co.]
    - 67. Boase Massimi Pollitt, All Time Greats, undated (Box 52)
    - 68. Chiat Day Inc. Advertising, agency reel, undated (Box 52)
      [Includes spots for Oral-B, 3M Company, California Cooler, Worlds of Wonder's Teddy Ruxpin, and Apple]
    - 69. Chiat Day Inc. Advertising, presentation reel, undated (Box 52)
      [Includes spots for Home Savings & Loan and Foster Farms]
    - 70. D & AD, TV & Cinema, 1980 (Box 53)
    - 71. Fallon McElligott Rice, U.S. West, The Dream, undated (Box 53)
    - 72. Fisher Advertising, 1987 (Box 53)
    - 73. Goodby, Berlin & Silverstein, agency reel, 1988 (Box 53)
    - 74. Reeves Communications, Issue No. 2, 1982 (Box 53)
      [Includes American Bell: O&M's Winning Presentation, Special Events Sponsorship: Extending Your Advertising Dollar]
    - 75. Reeves Communications, Preview Issue, 1982 (Box 53)
    - 76. J. Walter Thompson, Zap Proof, undated (Box 54)
    - 77. Livingston & Co., Alaska Airlines historical reel, undated (Box 54)
    - McKinney & Silver
      - 78. Mastercard, Spendthrift, 1990 (Box 54)
      - 79. Presentation reel, 1987 (Box 54)
        [Includes spots for Piedmont Airlines, NCNB, North Carolina DWI Campaign, Benihana]
      - 80. Presentation reel, 1988 (Box 54)
        [Includes spots for Benihana, Norweigan Cruise Line, NCNB, Piedmont, GoodMark Foods, Inc., North Carolina DWI, Carolina Power & Light]
      - 82. Presentation reel, 1988-04-26; 0:05:53 (Box 54, Video-cassette RL00878-UM-0001, Digital-materials RL00878-SET-0001)
        1. Norwegian Cruise Lines, "Radar"; 2. Piedmont, "First Class"; 3. Benihana, "Mysterious"; 4. Piedmont, "Vacation-Laid Back-DCA"; 5. CP and L, "Telephone"; 6. NCNB, "Nickel and Dime"; 7. Jesse Jones, "Airplane"; 8. DWI, "Tough Laws"; 9. Benihana, "Chuck Wagon"; 10. Piedmont, "Moon Map"
      - 81. Presentation reel, 1988 (Box 55)
      - 83. Presentation reel, undated (Box 55)
        [Includes spots for Piedmont, Carolina Power & Light, NCNB, SCNB]
      - 84. Presentation reel, undated (Box 55)
        [Includes spots for Piedmont, Tom's, NCNB, Carolina Power & Light]
      - 85. Presentation reel, undated (Box 55)
        [Includes spots for Pine State, Kingsdown, NCNB, Barnett Banks, GoodMark Foods, Inc. Jesse Jones Meats]
      - 86. Ralston Purina, Tough Morning, undated (Box 55)
      - 87. Television sample reel, 1985 (Box 55)
        [Includes spots for Piedmont, Benihana, South Carolina National Bank, Pine State, NCNB, Brown & Williamson, Carolina Power & Light]
      - 88. Time Pieces, 1989 (Box 55)
      - 89. Unidentified, undated (Box 56)
    - Out of Towner's Exhibit, 1986
      - 90. Martin Agency (Box 56)
      - 91. Miscellaneous agencies (Box 56)
        [Includes Fallon McElligott, Leonard Monahan Saabye, Livingston & Co., Martin Agency, M&S, Richards Group]
    - 92. Wieden & Kennedy, radio spots, undated (Box 56)
      [Includes spot for Nike, Inc.]
    - 93. WRAL-TV 5, Live at Noon segment on M&S, 1987 Jul. 30 (Box 56)
    - McKinney home videos, 1988
      - 94.-95. Tape 1 (Box 57)
      - 96.-97. Tape 2 (Box 57)
      - 98. Tape 3 (Box 57)
      - 99. Tape 4 (Box 57)
- Oversize Materials, 1964-1990 and undated, 13 boxes
  - Medium boxes, 1968-1990 and undated
    - General (Box OV1)
      - Administrative files
        - Agency floorplans, undated (Box OV1)
        - Agency organizational structure, undated (Box OV1)
      - Clippings
        - Advertising Age, marketing studies, 1975-1978 (Box OV1)
        - Financial reference, 1972-1977 (Box OV1)
        - General topics editorials, 1968-1977 (Box OV1)
        - Marketing research clippings, 1974-1977 (Box OV1)
        - Miscellaneous Advertising Age clippings, 1971-1978 (Box OV1)
        - Miscellaneous, 1976, 1990, n.d (Box OV1)
        - Miscellaneous business tips, 1972 (Box OV1)
        - Presentation reference, Rising Cost of T.V. Commercials, 1968 (Box OV1)
      - Memorabilia
        - Art Directors Club of Richmond, commemorative poster for Charles McKinney, 1968 (Box OV1)
    - Accounts
      - General accounts
        - Clippings, 1971, 1975 (Box OV1)
        - Production status review, 1978 (Box OV1)
      - Benihana, proofs, undated (Box OV2)
      - Carlyle, proofs, undated (Box OV2)
      - Coke, brochure, undated (Box OV2)
      - Del Monte Corporation, proofs, undated (Box OV2)
      - GoodMark Foods, Inc., Slim Jim
        - Proofs, undated (Box OV2)
        - Table of sales, 1979 (Box OV2)
      - Gravely, proofs, undated (Box OV2)
      - Jiffy Lube, strategic analysis and development, undated (Box OV2)
      - Karastan, proofs, undated (Box OV2)
      - Leader Federal Savings & Loan, proofs, undated (Box OV2)
      - Monk & Co., proofs, undated (Box OV2)
      - North Carolina Travel & Tourism, proofs, undated (Box OV2)
      - Norweigan Cruise Line, brand review and strategic implications, undated (Box OV2)
      - Piedmont (Box OV3)
        - Press, 1983 (Box OV3)
        - Sketches, undated, 3 folders (Box OV3)
      - Pizza Hut, proofs, undated (Box OV3)
      - Riceland Rice, proofs, undated (Box OV3)
      - Royal Caribbean Cruise Line, brand review and strategic implications, undated (Box OV3)
      - South Carolina Division of Tourism, proofs, undated (Box OV3)
      - South Carolina National Bank, proofs, undated (Box OV3)
      - Sterling Automotive, Strategic analysis and development, undated (Box OV3)
      - Xerox, proofs, undated (Box OV3)
    - Competitive (Box OV4)
      - Connecticut Williams, proofs, undated (Box OV4)
      - Ketchum Communications, general, undated (Box OV4)
      - Miscellaneous brochures, undated (Box OV4)
      - Unidentified agencies, proofs, undated (Box OV4)
    - New Business
      - Agency presentation, undated (Box OV4)
      - Clippings, 1988, undated (Box OV4)
      - Presentation charts, undated (Box OV4)
    - Printed Material
      - Lithographed Bordered Blanks and Certificates, undated (Box OV4)
      - Promotional material (Box OV5)
        - CBS, 1964, 1972, undated (Box OV5)
        - Miscellaneous promotional, undated, 2 folders (Box OV5)
      - Periodicals (Box OV6)
        - Advertising Age: 20th Century Advertising and the Economy of Abundance, 1980 (Box OV6)
        - Upper and Lowercase
          - 1977-1978, 2 folders (Box OV6)
          - 1979-1980, 2 folders (Box OV7)
          - 1981-1983, 3 folders (Box OV8)
  - Large boxes, 1979, 1982 and undated
    - Accounts (Box OV9)
      - American Drew, proofs, undated (Box OV9)
      - Barnett Banks, proofs, undated (Box OV9)
      - Clark, proofs, undated (Box OV9)
      - Fannie Mae, proofs, undated (Box OV10)
      - Hahn Tigers, proofs, 1979 (Box OV10)
      - North Carolina National Bank, proofs, undated (Box OV10)
      - Norweigan Cruise Line, proofs, undated (Box OV10)
      - Piedmont, proofs, undated (Box OV11)
      - Pine State, proofs, undated (Box OV11)
      - Royal Caribbean Cruise Line, proofs, undated (Box OV11)
      - Trim Milk, proofs, undated (Box OV11)
      - USAir Group, Inc., proofs, undated (Box OV11)
    - Competitive (Box OV12)
      - Scali, McCabe, Sloves, Inc., proofs, undated (Box OV12)
    - New Business
      - Agency proofs, undated (Box OV12)
      - Presentation booklet, undated (Box OV12)
    - Printed material
      - Creative newspaper, 1982 (Box OV12)
      - Decision model, undated (Box OV12)
      - Media charts, undated (Box OV12)
      - Miscellaneous promotional material, undated (Box OV12)
    - Piedmont Airlines model airplane, undated (Box OV13)
      [Plastic model airplane on pedestal printed with Piedmont logo, kept in McKinney's office.]